Guide to the Eric Alfred Havelock Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Professional Files, 1946-1988; Series II
  - Organizations
    - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), 1964-1966 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - American Philological Association, 1963-1977 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - American Philosophical Association, 1966-1967 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Center for Hellenic Studies, Washington, D.C., 1963-1987, undated (Box 17, Folder 38-40)
    - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1979, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, 1975-1976, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Institute of Man and Science, Rensselaerville, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - International Society for Homeric Studies, 1970-1977 (Box 18, Folder 44-45)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities [Senior Fellowship], 1968-1973 (Box 18, Folder 46)
- Canadian Files, 1925-1980; Series III
  The Canadian files, arranged alphabetically by organization, and by topic within the organization, document Havelock's political views and activities, as well as his contributions to the field of classics, during his years in Canada. Emphasis is on the founding and work of the Co-operative Commonwealth Federation (CCF) and the League of Social Reconstruction (LSR). The files include correspondence; reports; constituency files; campaign and election materials; publicity; writings; and related printed materials.
  On the academic front, there are files on the Ontario Classical Association, of which Havelock was a co-founder and first president. A minimal amount of writings on education are included at the end of the series. For teaching and research materials corresponding to Havelock's years as a professor in Canada, consult Series V, Writings, Research, and Teaching Files.
  - Correspondence ["preservable"], 1930, 1935-1949 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Canadian organizations
    - Civil Liberties Association of Toronto, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Co-operative Commonwealth Federation (CCF) [Ontario section]
      - General, 1934-1937, 1940, 1941, 1944-1948, undated (Box 19, Folder 3-14)
      - Annual Provincial Convention, 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 15-17)
        General note
        See also: Oversize, Box 64
      - Anthems, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Campaign conference [second], 1945 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Campaign letter to overseas personnel, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Campaign poster [Havelock as provincial candidate]
        See: Oversize,Box 64
      - CCF NEWS
      - Conference [farmers and trade unions], 1946 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Constituency files
        - General [notebooks of EAH], Undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
        - General correspondence/chart, 1944-1945, undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
          See also: Oversize,Box 64
        - Algoma East, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 24)
        - Algoma West, 1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
        - Brandtford, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 26)
        - Brant, 1944-1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
        - Carleton, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 28)
        - Cochrane, 1944, undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
        - Dufferin-Simcoe, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 30)
        - Durham, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 31)
        - Essex West and East, 1943-1945 (Box 20, Folder 32)
        - Frontenac-Addington, 1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 33)
        - Grey North, 1944-1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 34)
        - Kingston, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 35)
        - Lincoln, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 36)
        - Middlesex W, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 37)
        - Muskoka, 1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 38)
        - Nipissing, 1944-1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 39)
        - Ontario, 1943-1945 (Box 20, Folder 40)
        - Ottawa, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 41)
        - Peel, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 42)
        - Spadina, 1938, 1942-1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 43 - 45)
        - Toronto, 1944-1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 46)
        - Victoria, 1944-1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 47)
        - Wellington South and North, 1944-1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 48)
        - Constituency organizers, training of, 1944, undated (Box 20, Folder 49)
      - Constitution/amendments, 1942-1944 (Box 21, Folder 50)
      - Co-operative Bulletin, 1944 December (Box 21, Folder 51)
      - Co-operative Commonwealth Youth Movement, 1933-1934, 1944-1945, undated (Box 21, Folder 52)
      - Education
        - Background materials, 1943-1945 (Box 21, Folder 53-56)
        - Education coordinator, 1945, undated (Box 21, Folder 57)
        - Woodsworth House, 1941, 1945-1946, undated (Box 21, Folder 58 - 61)
      - Election Campaign Conference, 1945 March (Box 21, Folder 62)
      - Election Committee, 1945, undated (Box 21, Folder 63)
      - Election publicity, 1945, undated (Box 21, Folder 64)
      - Election tactics, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 65)
      - Electoral Committee, 1945, undated (Box 21, Folder 66)
      - Electoral data, 1944-1945, undated (Box 21, Folder 67)
      - Ephemera [printed materials], 1933-1935, 1944-1947, undated (Box 21, Folder 68-69)
      - Executive Committee, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 70)
      - Federal election issues, 1935, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 71-72)
      - Federal Steering Committee, 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 73)
      - Finances, 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 74)
      - Founding of CCF, 1932-1934, undated (Box 22, Folder 75)
      - Labor-Progressive Party, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 76)
      - Legislative Assembly, 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 77)
      - Lists of Parliament members, unions, candidates, and CCF leaders, 1943-1945, undated (Box 22, Folder 78-79)
      - National conventions, 1936-1939, 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 80-82)
      - New Commonwealth, 1934-1939, 1945, undated (Box 22, Folder 83)
      - News Comment, 1944 September 1 (Box 22, Folder 84)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1943, 1944, undated (Box 22, Folder 85)
      - Notes/notebook [on socialism], Undated (Box 22, Folder 86-87)
      - "Notice Board"/"Office News", 1944-1946, undated (Box 22, Folder 88)
      - Ontario [general information, policy report], 1946-1947, undated (Box 22, Folder 89-90)
      - Oshawa strike speech, 1935-1939, 1947, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 91-92)
      - Provincial Education Committee [meeting minutes], 1946-1947 (Box 23, Folder 93)
      - Provincial Election Committee, 1943-1944, undated (Box 23, Folder 94)
      - Provincial Executive/Council meetings [minutes and reports], 1942 September-1946 (Box 23, Folder 95-99)
      - Publications, flyers, 1933, 1940, 1943-1947 (Box 23, Folder 100-101)
      - Radio scripts [includes speeches by E. B. Jolliffe], 1945-1946, undated (Box 23, Folder 102-103)
      - "Socialist Dogma Reexamined", [1938?] (Box 23, Folder 104)
      - Speech notes [re CCF and Canadian political issues], 1944-1945, undated (Box 24, Folder 105-107)
      - Stafford Printers, Ltd., 1935-1939 (Box 24, Folder 108)
      - Summer school [work group on socialist principles], Undated (Box 24, Folder 109)
      - Toronto and Yorks Electoral Conference, 1944-1945, undated (Box 24, Folder 110)
      - Toronto Regional Council, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 111)
      - Trade Union Committee, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 112)
      - Trade Union Conference, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 113)
      - Underhill, Frank, 1969-1971 (Box 24, Folder 114)
      - University of Toronto
        - Hart House [includes Woodsworth], 1930, 1931 (Box 24, Folder 115)
        - Victoria College, 1944-1945 (Box 24, Folder 116)
    - Federal Union (Canada) [re creation of a world government association], 1944-1945 (Box 24, Folder 117)
    - Fellowship for a Christian Social Order, 1932-1937, 1941-1942, 1980, undated (Box 24, Folder 118-121)
    - League for Social Reconstruction (LSR)
      - 1930-1939 (Box 24, Folder 122-130)
      - 1940-1941, undated (Box 25, Folder 131-133)
    - Ontario Classical Association, 1944-1948, undated (Box 25, Folder 134-137)
    - Student League of Canada [ The Spark ], 1932, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 138)
  - Writings
    - "Canada's Way Out", Undated (Box 25, Folder 139)
    - Lectures [series of ten lectures on world events in the early 1930s; Public Library of Toronto] (Box 25, Folder 140)
    - Published articles [in various political and student publications; includes topics on education], [1925?]-1941, undated (Box 25, Folder 141-142)
    - Saturday Night: The Canadian Illustrated Weekly [articles by EAH], 1940 (Box 25, Folder 143)
  - Newspapers/clippings [on Canadian/British politics, government, education], 1940s-1970s, undated (Box 25, Folder 144 - 145)
  - Printed materials [primarily on trade unions, government agencies, post war measures], 1944-1945, undated (Box 25, Folder 146-147)
- Personal Papers and Photographs, 1903-1989; Series IV
  The series is arranged in two sections: personal papers and photographs. The bulk of the personal papers section consists of materials amassed by Havelock for his unfinished autobiography, which he began writing in the early 1980s. A chapter draft, entitled "An Edwardian Childhood," completed in 1983, was intended by him "...as an installment leading into some account of my adult life, as lived mainly in North America, but keeping in mind the historical context of two world wars, and reflections stimulated thereby." His files consist primarily of newspaper and journal clippings, as well as correspondence, notes, and memorabilia, often heavily annotated with questions and/or observations. The files have been maintained in their original order and are arranged in a chronological time frame corresponding to time periods in Havelock's life. Thus folders may contain research materials from 1980s sources but refer to an event or person for an earlier time period. Other files are arranged by topic but still adhere to a basic chronological order; some files are unsorted. The remainder of the series includes academic certificates, legal documents, memoriams, and memorabilia of Havelock. Photographs of Havelock and family members complete the series.
  - Personal papers
    - Autobiography, unfinished [drafts, research files, and notes]
      - "An Edwardian Childhood" [chapter one drafts, notes], 1983 (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
      - 1903-1917 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Pre-1926 (Box 26, Folder 5-13)
      - Pre-1926 (Box 27, Folder 14-16)
      - Nova Scotia, 1926-1929 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - CCF [early protest document], 1929-1939 (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - CCF [clippings], 1970 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - 1929-1946 (Box 27, Folder 20 - 26)
      - Toronto, LSR, Undated (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - Harvard/Radcliffe, Undated (Box 28, Folder 28-36)
      - Hellenic Center, Undated (Box 28, Folder 37)
      - 1944-1952 (Box 28, Folder 38)
      - 1960s (Box 28, Folder 39)
        Clippings.
      - From Harvard to Yale, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 40)
      - Yale, 1960s-1970s (Box 29, Folder 41-43)
      - European visit, 1965-1966 (Box 29, Folder 44)
      - Non-Augean, 1963-1971 (Box 29, Folder 45)
      - Augean, 1963-1981 (Box 29, Folder 46-48)
      - Revolt in the desert, 1963-1966, Undated (Box 30, Folder 49-52)
      - Emeritus [Andrew V. Raymond Chair], 1973-1981 (Box 31, Folder 53-54)
      - Authorship, Undated (Box 31, Folder 55)
      - Classical re-evaluation, 1956-1987 (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Guggenheim Fellow, 1940, 1943, 1949, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 57-59)
      - Intellectual climate, Undated (Box 31, Folder 60-63)
      - Profession of classics, Undated (Box 31, Folder 64-65)
      - Only in America, Undated (Box 31, Folder 66)
      - Social Democrat, Undated (Box 31, Folder 67)
      - CIA/Cold War, Undated (Box 31, Folder 68-70)
      - CIA/Cold War, Undated (Box 32, Folder 71-73)
      - Education, Undated (Box 32, Folder 74)
      - Israel, Undated (Box 32, Folder 75-76)
      - Reagan, Undated (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Nuclear war, Undated (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - Political, Undated (Box 32, Folder 79)
      - Russia, Undated (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Return to England, Undated (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Reflections, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 82-84)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1977-1980 (Box 33, Folder 85-90)
      - Newspaper clippings, unsorted, Undated (Box 33, Folder 91-96)
      - Verse, 1939, undated (Box 33, Folder 97)
      - My intellectual progression from Cornford to Concept, Undated (Box 33, Folder 98)
    - Biographical/bibliography, Undated (Box 34, Folder 99-101)
    - British refugee children [correspondence, photographs], 1940 (Box 34, Folder 102)
    - Certificates/degrees
    - Death certificates/documents, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 103)
    - England, 1971, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 104)
    - Estate of E. A. Havelock [executor's accounts and related family correspondence], 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 105)
    - Memorabilia [driver's licenses], 1926, 1931, 1983, undated (Box 34, Folder 106)
    - Memoriams/obituaries/condolences, 1988-1989 (Box 34, Folder 107-108)
    - Parry, Adam ["In Memoriam," by E. A. Havelock and Hugh Lloyd-Jones], 1975, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 109)
    - Prose sketches, juvenalia, translations, Circa 1920s-1940s, undated (Box 34, Folder 110-113)
  - Photographs
    - Havelock, Eric [includes family members], 1903, 1923-1939, 1955, 1962-1967, 1976-1986, undated (Box 34, Folder 114-116)
    - Yale Classics Department party, Late 1960s (Box 34, Folder 117)
- Writings, Research, and Teaching Files, 1930-1988; Series V
  This series, the largest in the papers, is described in the order in which the papers were received. Materials have been left in their original binders and/or folders and the spine/label information constitutes the listing. Most of the materials are in Havelock's handwriting and consist of book drafts; course notes and lectures; and subject files of printed materials. Whenever possible, course materials are identified by course number and include lecture notes, class assignments, exams, and related research materials.
  - Early essays/notes, 1930s-1940s
    - Aristotle (Box 35)
    - Herodotus (Box 35)
    - Plato's aristocratic bias (Box 35)
    - Communication in wartime (Box 35)
    - Cornford lectures (Box 35)
    - Epicurean canonic (Box 35)
    - Galsworthy, John (Box 35)
    - Hardy, Thomas (Box 35)
    - Limitations of Plato's politics (Box 35)
    - Notes, unidentified (Box 35)
    - Pre-Socratic doxographics (Box 35)
    - Propaganda, British/German (Box 35)
    - Religious articles (Box 35)
    - Current events (Box 35)
  - America and England, 1940, 1941, undated (Box 36)
  - Socialism and government, 1930s (Box 36)
  - The Body Politic, The Common People, 1930s (Box 36)
  - Conditions of peace, 1942, undated (Box 36)
  - Economics/political, Undated (Box 36)
  - Germany past and present, 1941, undated (Box 36)
  - Literature of Social Revolt [notes for course given to Workers' Education Association], [1933?] (Box 36)
  - The Metaphysics of the Milesian School [typescript], Undated (Box 36)
  - Modern English literature, [1932?] (Box 36)
  - The One and the Many [paper submitted to American Philological Association], 1936 (Box 36)
  - Parmenides, Undated (Box 36)
  - Pre-Socratics, Undated (Box 36)
  - Proto-Comology, Undated (Box 36)
  - Pythagoras, Pythagoreans, Undated (Box 36)
  - Sophists/Pythagoras, 1970, undated (Box 36)
  - Victoria College
    - Classical humanities course, 1938-1944, undated (Box 36)
    - Debating Parliament, 1943-1946, undated (Box 36)
    - Zeno-Melissus, Undated (Box 36)
  - Homer's Odyssey, Undated (Box 37)
  - Greek 1a, Undated (Box 37)
  - Greek 112a, Plato, 1950s (Box 37)
  - Greek 107b, Greek Political Theory, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Humanities
    - Undated (Box 37)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 37)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 37)
    - S101C [summer school], 1953 (Box 37)
    - 1b, 1947 (Box 37)
    - Lucretius, 1949-1950 (Box 37)
    - I [correspondence], 1954-1955 (Box 37)
    - Applications, Early 1950s (Box 37)
    - I [readings, assignments, exams, essay topics], 1949-1955 (Box 37)
  - Lecture notes, Greek/Latin, Undated (Box 38)
  - Greek 107b, Political Theory in Greece, 450-350 B.C., 1953-1954, undated (Box 38)
  - Greek Ba, Socrates, 1947 (Box 38)
  - Lucretius, Undated (Box 38)
  - Latin 8b, Lucretius, 1947-1948 (Box 38)
  - Platonism, Undated (Box 38)
  - Plato's Republic, 1966-1970 (Box 38)
  - Plato's Republic /Greek 108a [running analysis], Undated (Box 38)
  - Sight, Undated (Box 38)
  - Aristotle-Metaphysics [analysis; 98367, 980a27-989a15], Undated (Box 38)
  - Metaphysics A, Undated (Box 38)
  - Meta Language of Aristotle, Undated (Box 39)
  - Anaximandros, Undated (Box 39)
  - Meta-Analysis, Undated (Box 39)
  - Glossary of Mental Terms, Undated (Box 39)
  - Glossary of Physical Terms, Undated (Box 39)
  - Drama articles, Undated (Box 39)
  - Greek music, Undated (Box 39)
  - Bibliography on myths, Undated (Box 39)
  - Greek theatrical performance bibliography, Undated (Box 39)
  - Antigone, Undated (Box 39)
  - Comparative Literatures [four binders, lectures 1-28], 1950-1958 (Box 39)
  - Greek drama/ Oresteia, Undated (Box 39)
  - Oedipus, Undated (Box 40)
  - Problems in Greek drama, Undated (Box 40)
  - Drama, Undated (Box 40)
  - Drama front matter, Classical Civilization 35b, 1970 (Box 40)
  - Othello, Macbeth, Undated (Box 40)
  - Othello, London, Undated (Box 40)
  - Trojan women/Hippolytus, Undated (Box 40)
  - Virgilian materials, Undated (Box 40)
  - Virgil, history and Aeneid, Undated (Box 40)
  - Aeneid /books I-XII, 1949-1950 (Box 40)
  - Classics exams [Christ's, Emmanuel, and Sidney Sussex Colleges], Undated (Box 41)
  - University of Toronto [exams], 1940s (Box 41)
  - Hellenic Center/Intellectual history, 1966 (Box 41)
  - Latin translations, [1930s] (Box 41)
  - Crisis in university, schools of antiquity, Undated (Box 41)
  - Poetics, Undated (Box 41)
  - Greek art and Greek philosophy [Vassar], 1963 (Box 41)
  - Sophistication of Homer, Undated (Box 41)
  - Georges P. Vanier memorial lecture/conference, Undated (Box 41)
  - Plato's invention of the university-synopsis of Republic/middle comedy, Undated (Box 41)
  - War as a Way of Life in Classical Literature [notes, bibliography, University of Ottawa], 1970 (Box 41)
  - Greek verse/prose/iambic composition, Undated (Box 41)
  - Jaeger/Demos, 1958 (Box 41)
  - Written Records of the Greeks, Undated (Box 41)
  - On the Sanctification of Plato, Undated (Box 41)
  - Ancient and modern poetry, Undated (Box 41)
  - American mission, 1952 (Box 41)
  - Education, Undated (Box 41)
  - Socratic self, 1968 (Box 42)
  - Semple lectures, Undated (Box 42)
  - Origins, Undated (Box 42)
  - Birth, Undated (Box 42)
  - Oral Foundations of Hellenism, Undated (Box 42)
  - Literate Revolution in Greece and its European Consequences [four lectures delivered at Ontario Institute for Studies in Education], 1974 March (Box 42)
  - Typescript annotated drafts
    - Chapter 5-Storage of Information, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 7-Psychology of Rhythmic Memorisation, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 9-The First Four Hundred Years, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 10-Real World of Homer, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 14-The Homeric Verb "einai" and the Syntax of the Oral Tradition, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 15-The Legal Structure of the Iliad, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 16- The Legal Structure of the Odyssey, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 17-The Moral Structure of the Odyssey, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 18-The Alphabetization of Homer, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 19-Documentation of Discourse and its Consequences, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 20-The Syntax of the Written Word, Undated (Box 42)
    - Chapter 21-Hesiod, the Knowledge-Maker, Undated (Box 42)
  - Early papers, notes, reprints, 1940s-1950s (Box 42)
  - Heraclitus [handwritten English translation], Undated (Box 42)
  - Euripides [synopses of plays], Undated (Box 42)
  - Theophrastus, Undated (Box 42)
  - Bemays' Letters of Heraclitus [English translation] (Box 42)
  - Demosthenes chronology, notes, Undated (Box 42)
  - Plato [articles, reprints], Undated (Box 42)
  - Platonic scholarship, Undated (Box 42)
  - Democritus, Undated (Box 42)
  - Political analysis, Undated (Box 42)
  - Pythagoras, Undated (Box 42)
  - Virgil, Orpheus, and Eurydice, Undated (Box 42)
  - Catullus and Poe, Undated (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 42)
  - Significance of Socrates [notes], 1944 (Box 43)
  - Socratic problem [bibliography], 1965 (Box 43)
  - Was Socrates Literate?, Undated (Box 43)
  - Critiques of Vlastos, Santas, Guthrie, Dover, Irwin [notes], Undated (Box 43)
  - Clouds, Undated (Box 43)
  - Search for Socratic Doctrine, Undated (Box 43)
  - Translation of the Clouds, Undated (Box 43)
  - Man of Athens, Undated (Box 43)
  - Virgil/Georg IV/Cyrene, Undated (Box 43)
  - The Orality of Socrates and the Literacy of Plato [typescript, second version], Undated (Box 43)
  - Pliny [bibliography], Undated (Box 43)
  - St. Augustine, Social Sciences, 1949-1950 (Box 43)
  - Why was Socrates Tried?, Undated (Box 43)
  - Socrates [bibliography], Undated (Box 43)
  - Stenzel's notes on Socrates, Undated (Box 43)
  - Greek anthropology [four binders, Homer to Plato: Greek Concept of Justice, analysis, concept notes unused, concept material-leftover material], Undated (Box 43)
  - Homer to Plato (Box 43)
    - Footnotes to preface, Undated (Box 44)
    - Prometheus, Undated (Box 44)
    - Old Testament, Undated (Box 44)
    - The Rim Round the Shield/ Iliad [chapter 13], Undated (Box 44)
    - The Falling Anvil/space integration in Hesiod, Undated (Box 44)
    - Dinaiosune?, Protagoras, Xerxes Bridge, Undated (Box 44)
    - Socratic problem, Undated (Box 44)
    - Oracles of Achilles, Undated (Box 44)
    - Socrates: A Study in the Origin of Intellectual Man [vol. I, chapters 1-8, carbon typescript], Undated (Box 44)
    - Socrates [vol. I, II, part III], Undated (Box 44)
    - Socrates and Plato, Undated (Box 44)
    - Plato's Method of Defeating Liberalism [typescript], Undated (Box 44)
    - Concerning Hesiod, Undated (Box 44)
    - Theognidea, Damian?, etc. [early notes], Undated (Box 44)
  - The Origins of Intellectual Man [also described as History of Growth of Greek Mind; notes, chapter synopses 1-8, footnotes], Undated (Box 45)
  - Pinax notes, Undated (Box 46)
  - Logos, Undated (Box 46)
  - Logos, Cosmos, One, Exposition, Estate of Man, Nature of Man [notes], Undated (Box 46)
  - Cosmos, The One and the Many, Technique of Exposition, Undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Cosmic patterns of Thales-Xenoph..., Undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Cosmic patterns of Heraclitus, Parmenides, Undated (Box 46)
  - Cosmologies based on Lucretius/Meterologies based on Aristotle, Undated (Box 46)
  - Integration/Integration of Moral Experience, Undated (Box 46)
  - Estate, Nature, Civilization of Men, Undated (Box 46)
  - Notes-civil-Enlightenment, Undated (Box 46)
  - Ionia/Athens, Undated (Box 46)
  - Hecataeus, Undated (Box 46)
  - PreSocratic lectures [Toronto], Undated (Box 47)
  - Preface to PreSocratics, miscellaneous, Undated (Box 47)
  - History of Greek mind, Undated (Box 47)
  - Athenian Enlightenment [chapter 16], Undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Political theory [chapter 17], chapter 18, Undated (Box 47)
  - Ionia and Athens/Companions of Socrates, Paideia, Cardinal Habits, Proto-Morality, Conscious Ethic, Struggle Within, Wits and Senses, Abstract... [chapters 14-19, chapter numbers vary], Undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Untitled, Undated (Box 47)
  - Loose handwritten papers on variety of topics, Undated (Box 47)
  - Preliteracy, the PreSocratics [vol. I, II], Undated (Box 47)
  - My Father--Irving Fisher, by I.N. Fisher, Undated (Box 47)
  - Introduction to Classics 105a [Problems in the Language of Greek Philosophy], 1967 (Box 47)
  - Early Greek Anthologies, Undated (Box 47)
  - Milesians, Undated (Box 47)
  - Classical Civilization 28B [Atomism and Greek Science], Undated (Box 47)